Guide to the Ezra Cornell Papers, 1746-1888
Cornell, Ezra Papers, 1746-1888
- Series VIII: Scrapbooks, Broadsides, Maps, Photographs, Clippings, Ephemera, and Genealogical Information
  - Unknown note regarding trip to Washington with Ezra Cornell, son and Rev. D. Torrey (July 23, 1867) (Box 100, Folder 5)
  - Framed stock certificate (Box 101)
    Ezra Cornell's 250 shares of capital stock of the Ithaca & Cortland Railroad Company (July 8, 1871)
  - Cornell Family Bible (Box 103)
  - Clippings, maps, and printed materials (Map-case Folder 4)
    Ithaca Journal pages relating to the death of Ezra Cornell; maps and floor plans pertaining to Ithaca, Cornell Public Library, and Cornell University; other clippings and printed materials.
  - Maps (Map-case Folder 5)
    Maps of Wisconsin, including Barron County and village of Cornell; Traveler's map of the Middle, Northern, Eastern States and Canada, showing all the railroad, steamboat, canal, and principal stage routes, 1849; Maps of railroad routes; maps of Minnesota, 1865 and Mackinaw City, 1857; other printed maps.
  - Ezra Cornell's pocket knife, MU-3006; Undated (Box 102)
    Includes a letter from 1947 from Charles H. Blair describing the knife and its use.
  - Ezra Cornell's small folding scale ruler, Undated; MU-3007 (Box 102)
  - Ezra Cornell's compass, embedded in Tiger's Eye stone, Undated; MU-3008 (Box 102)
  - Silver pocket knife, engraved with E. Cornell, 1873-12-25; MU-3009 (Box 102)